Kensuke Morris

Data Analyst

Contact

Objective

Kyoto City, Japan +8138319243 kensuke.morris@gmail.com LinkedIn Data analyst skilled in data exploration and communicating data insights from multiple standpoints to solve business and research problems. especially for culture-specific projects. Previously utilized combined quantitative and qualitative methods to develop a patient-centered proposal for patient data sharing on a nationwide level.

Education

Projects

Certificate in Data Analytics | 2/2021 - 9/2021CareerFoundry (Online) Intense, project-based courses

Emergency Department Discharge Encounters

View

Conducted a preliminary investigation of patient encounters related to patient race groups and ED discharge types in California using Python and Tableau.

Ph.D. in Informatics | 2020 Minor in Design Kyoto University

Instacart Customer Behaviour

View

MS in Informatics | 2017 Kyoto University Performed an initial data and exploratory analysis of customer data to derive insights and suggested strategies for better customer segmentation using Python and Tableau.

Rockbuster Films Sales Planning

View

B.Sc. Info. Technology | 2014 St. George's University Answered business questions relating film sales and customer locations posed by Rockbuster's Management Board to inform their strategic plans using SQL and Excel.

Key Skills

Experience

Research Fellow • 4/2021 - current

National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center • Japan

Data-driven Inquiry Data Cleaning Data Exploration **Database Querying** Statistical Analysis Regression Analysis Machine Learning Storytelling Team Coordination

- Obtained valuable insights for a healthcare device company using health
- related data. Utilized survival and regression analysis techniques. • Selected predictive features of patients with a cardiovascular-related disease using the boruta technique, random forest, and lasso/ridge regression.

Activities

Researcher • 10/2020 – 3/2021 Kyoto University Hospital • Japan

Teams Coordinator | 2018 Hult Prize On Campus Event • Developed the first draft API documentation based on my Ph.D. research related to patient data sharing to assist a health records vendor in developing tools to future system integration.

President | 2014 Undergrad. Student Gov't.

• Coached and supported colleagues and students in developing their research techniques related to user research, especially quantitative survey design and interview techniques.

Languages

Software: Python | PostgreSQL | R | HTML

Spoken: English (Native) | Japanese (Conversation) | Spanish (Elementary)